So, now, imagine that we want to look at the same thing,
假设我们只有 2 个潜在特征
but, say, we only have two latent features instead.
其他不变
So, we could make something that's maybe a little bit more extendable.
我们希望代码更加灵活
So, what we want to do is from the original u,
对于原始 U 矩阵
we still want all the rows.
我们依然想要保留所有行
We want the number of columns to k. Then,
列数有 k 个然后
to make something that's more reproducible than what we did before,
为了使操作比之前更容易重现
let's first start out with creating this matrix,
我们先创建这个矩阵
that's k by k. Then,
即 k x k 矩阵然后
what we'll do is we'll take the components
我们将获取分量本身
themselves and put in the k number of the diagonal elements in there.
并放入 k 个对角线元素
So, what this is doing is just pulling those first two elements.
这部分代码的作用是提取前 2 个元素
But if we change this to four,
如果将这个改成 4
then that's exactly what we saw before.
则与我们之前看到的完全一样
If we change it to three,
如果改成 3
then it's going to pull three of them.
则提取前 3 个元素
Okay. So, I think that should work.
Ok应该没什么问题
Then, basically, with this,
接下来
we now need to subset it to
我们将获得一个子集
the number of latent features on the row and all of the movies on the columns.
行数为潜在特征的数量 列数为所有电影数量
So, it looks like those things match up with the shapes they're supposed to be.
这些形状看起来满足预期
Finally, what they're asking us to do is to compute
最后 我们需要计算
the dot product between each of those matrices.
每个矩阵之间的点积
So, we'll take the dot product of u and s with two latent features.
我们将计算 U 和 S 的点积 潜在特征是 2 个
Then, what we want to do is we want to the dot product of
然后计算这个矩阵
that matrix with two.
与 vt_2 的点积
That should give us our predicted ratings.
这样就能获得预期的评分
I'm going to pull this out too.
我将这行代码复制到这里
So, if we were to do this with all four of them,
如果使用所有 4 个潜在特征
we would have just gotten the matrix back,
则获得矩阵本身
itself, the original matrix.
即原始矩阵
But here's our predictions.
而这是预测结果
Then, we can compare the difference between the predicted and the actual.
我们可以比较预测值与实际值之间的差异
So, if we take user_movie,
获取 user_movie_subset...
I'm just going to comment this out really quick.
我将快速注释掉这一行
So, we take the difference.
如果计算差异的话
Basically, this is now an array of those differences.
这是包含所有差异的数组
If we want to know how much we were off by across all of them,
要查看所有差异偏离了多少
what we might do is compute their squared differences,
我们需要计算平方差
and then just sum them up.
然后相加
So, one of the sums,
一个 sum()
we'll take it across the columns.
将计算列上的和
Then, the other, we'll take it across the rows.
另一个 sum() 将计算行上的和
Cool.
好的
If we just take this part here, goes here.
将这部分放到这里
So, hopefully, that makes sense.
希望你听明白了
So, we're taking the difference between the actual and the subset.
我们计算的是实际数据集与子集的差异
If we look at the squared differences,
如果计算平方差
then, they all become positive.
那么都是正数
Then, if we take the sum of those,
然后求和
we can get an idea of basically how well we're doing at computing
这样我们就能判断使用 2 个潜在特征
the original matrix with only two latent features as opposed to using all four.
计算原始矩阵与使用 4 个潜在特征相比效果如何
So, let's say we did this with
将这些改成 new
new and if we look at the sum.
然后求和
So, you can see it's 6.49 times 10 to the negative 28.
结果是 6.49 e -28
So, it's essentially zero and that's probably just rounding errors.
本质上是 0 可能是因为四舍五入导致的错误
There's a six with 27 zeros in front of it before you hit a decimal point.
6 前面有 27 个 0 然后是小数点
Okay. I'm going to change this back just so- hopefully,
Ok我将这些再改回来
we pass the test. So, it looks great.
希望能通过测试看起来没问题
Now, the next thing that we're going to do is,
接下来 我们将尝试
we're going to try to calculate singular value decomposition when we add a nan in.
在添加一个 NaN 的情况下计算奇异值分解结果
So, if we just take the same line that we had up here,
复制下之前在上面
where we're actually computing
计算奇异值分解时用到的这行代码
the singular value decomposition, we can go back down here.
然后再回到这里
If we run the cell,
运行这个单元格
you'll notice that we get an error.
你会发现 我们遇到了一个错误
So, it says, "SVD did not converge."
错误消息是“svd did not converge.”
The main reason why that happened,
主要原因是
it's because you have a nan value.
有一个 NaN 值
So, next, we'll take a look at a strategy we can
接下来我们将学习一个策略
use when our matrices do not have a value in every cell.
当有些单元格没有值时可以采用该策略